In this clip I will tell you how to know a color of a diamond.
A color of a diamond is basically the shade of a diamond.
The shades are described in alphabetical order starting from D. Now here if you look at the design, there are D, E, F, G, H, I, J, and it goes up to Zed.
D, E, F, are considered to be white diamonds.
And as we go down to G, H, they are slightly tinted white.
And when we go to I, J, they are slightly tinted yellow.
And as we keep on going down the shades keep on decreasing.
Now, I show you just to give you a brief example, I show you the two diamonds just to know the difference between the colors.
Here, I have one piece which is a white diamond.
This diamond is D in color.
Now, I show you the other piece, now I show you the other piece, this piece is J in color.
Now if you compare these two stones you will get to know the difference in the color of a diamond.
So as the color goes up, up till D, the prices goes up, and as the color comes down to the slightly tinted yellow the prices will come down.
So you can see the difference, the shade and the prices are identically proportion to each other.
So now I hope you know how to choose the color of a diamond.
Thank you.